Clement Fung

Email: clementf@andrew.cmu.edu Website: https://clementfung.me

SUMMARY

Machine learning models present a unique threat model. As a result, when machine learning is integrated into real-world systems, the underlying assumptions and threats change. My research explores how these changes affect the privacy and security of such systems when they are deployed for real-world use. Most notably, I am interested in attacks and defenses for distributed multi-party machine learning systems (such as federated learning) and the security of machine-learning-based cyber-physical systems.

PUBLICATIONS

Refereed publications

• Biscotti: A Blockchain System for Private and Secure Federated Learning

Muhammad Shayan, <u>Clement Fung</u>, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh. IEEE Transactions on <u>Parallel and Distributed Systems (TPDS)</u>

Volume 32, Issue 7. July 2021.

• Towards a Lightweight, Hybrid Approach for Detecting DOM XSS Vulnerabilities with Machine Learning

William Melicher, Clement Fung, Lujo Bauer, Limin Jia.

The Web Conference 2021

Ljubjana, Slovenia (Virtual). April 2021.

• The Limitations of Federated Learning in Sybil Settings

Clement Fung, Chris J.M Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh.

23rd International Symposium on Research in Attacks, Intrusions and Defenses (RAID 2020) Donostia/San Sebastian, Spain (Virtual). October 2020.

• Brokered Agreements in Multi-Party Machine Learning

Clement Fung, Ivan Beschastnikh.

10th ACM SIGOPS Asia-Pacific Workshop on Systems (APSys 2019)

Hangzhou, China, August 2019.

• GainForest: Scaling Climate Finance for Forest Conservation using Interpretable Machine Learning on Satellite Imagery

David Dao, Catherine Cang, Clement Fung, Ming Zhang, Nick Pawlowski, Reuven Gonzales, Nick Beglinger, Ce Zhang.

Climate Change: How Can AI Help?: ICML 2019 Workshop

Long Beach, CA, June 2019.

Pre-prints

• Dancing in the Dark: Private Multi-Party Machine Learning in an Untrusted Setting Clement Fung, Jamie Koerner, Stewart Grant, Ivan Beschastnikh.

<u>ArXiv Preprint</u>: 1811.09712

November 2018.

• Mitigating Sybils in Federated Learning Poisoning

Clement Fung, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh.

ArXiv Preprint: 1808.04866

August 2018.

EDUCATION

PhD, Societal Computing, School of Computer Science

2019 - present

 $Carnegie\ Mellon\ University,\ Pittsburgh,\ PA$

Cumulative GPA: 3.87 / 4

Research Projects:

- DOM-XSS-ML: A hybrid, machine learning system to detect DOM-XSS with reduced overhead
- ICS-ML: Systems for securing industrial control systems with machine learning

Graduate Courses:

- 18731 Network Security (*Prof. Vyas Sekar*)
- 17762 Law of Computer Technology (*Prof. Michael Shamos*)
- 36700 Probability and Mathematical Statistics (*Prof. Valerie Ventura*)
- 18739 Security and Fairness of Deep Learning (Prof. Piotr Mardziel)
- 18730 Introduction to Computer Security (Prof. Virgil Gligor)

MSc, Computer Science

2016 - 2018

University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC Cumulative GPA: 88 / 100

Thesis:

• Dancing in the Dark: Private Multi-Party Machine Learning in an Untrusted Setting. Supervisor: Ivan Beschastnikh

Achievements:

- UBC CS Department Graduate Teaching Assistant Award, 2017
- UBC CS Department Student Service Award, 2017

Research Projects:

- Biscotti: A secure, private blockchain-based system for multi-party machine learning
- FoolsGold: A sybil-resilient federated learning protocol against model poisoning
- TorMentor: A system for distributed, collaborative, anonymous machine learning
- InsuLearn: A system for distributed learning on private medical data
- DistributedClocks: A library for vector clock instrumentation of distributed systems

Graduate Courses:

- CPSC 532R Graphical Models (Prof. Siamak Ravanbakhsh)
- CPSC 540 Advanced Machine Learning (*Prof. Mark Schmidt*)
- CPSC 538W Data At Scale (Prof. Andrew Warfield)
- CPSC 538B Distributed Systems (*Prof. Ivan Beschastnikh*)
- CPSC 340 Machine Learning (Prof. Mark Schmidt)

BASc, Systems Design Engineering (Dean's Honour's List Distinction)

2011 - 2016

University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON

Cumulative GPA: 88 / 100

Capstone Project:

• Driven: A Automated System for Intelligent Annotation and Analysis of Lane Change Sentiment Supervisor: Alexander Wong

Awards:

- Sanford Fleming Award for Co-operative Proficiency, 2016
- GM Canada Innovation Award, 2016 \$500
- W.W. King Exchange Fellowship, 2015 \$500
- President's International Experience Award, 2014 \$1500
- Sanford Fleming Award for Outstanding Communication in Work Term Report, 2013 \$300
- Colonel Hugh Heasley Engineering Scholarship, 2011 \$10000
- University of Waterloo President's Scholarship of Distinction, 2011 \$2000

Achievements:

- Dean's Honour's List, Winter 2016 Rank unknown
- Dean's Honour's List, Winter 2013 Ranked 2nd / 81 students
- Dean's Honour's List, Spring 2012 Ranked 2nd / 85 students
- Dean's Honour's List, Fall 2011 Ranked 3rd / 94 students

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant University of British Columbia	Sept 2016 - Dec 2018
• DSCI 571: Supervised Learning	Fall 2018

Instructors: Michael Gelbart, Varada Kolhatkar

• DSCI 523: Data Wrangling

Fall 2018

Instructors: Jenny Bryan, Rodolfo Lourenzutti

• CPSC 340: Machine Learning
Instructor: Michael Gelbart

CPSC 340: Machine Learning
Winter 2018

• CPSC 340: Machine Learning
Instructor: Mark Schmidt

Fall 2017

• CPSC 210: Software Construction Winter 2017 Instructors: Norman Hutchinson, Paul Carter, Mehrdad Oveisi

• CPSC 210: Software Construction Fall 2016 Instructors: Norman Hutchinson, Ryan Vogt, Jonatan Schroeder

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant August 2019 - present

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA, USA

• Research on machine learning, security and the industrial internet-of-things in CyLab.

Software Engineer

January 2019 - July 2019

Oasis Labs, Berkeley, CA, USA

• Developed applications for secure data sharing and other confidential use cases in an early stage blockchain startup.

Research Assistant

January 2017 - December 2018

University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada

 Research on the security of machine learning systems in the Networks, Systems and Security (NSS) Lab.

Software Engineering Intern

June - August 2015

LinkedIn Corporation, Sunnyvale, CA, USA

• Analytics: Building infrastructure for online relevance scoring at scale

Software Engineering Intern

September 2014 - December 2014

LinkedIn Corporation, Mountain View, CA, USA

• Distributed Data Systems: Prototyped and designed new derived data serving system, Venice

Software Engineering Intern

January 2014 - April 2014

Voicebox Technologies, Bellevue, WA, USA

• Server and Tools: Implemented layer for concurrent database access on a mobile service

Software Developer

May 2013 - August 2013

Ontario Institute for Cancer Research, Toronto, ON

• Software developer in Paul Boutros' bioinformatics research group

Software Developer

September 2012 - December 2012

pVelocity, Toronto, ON

QA Analyst

January 2012 - April 2012

pVelocity, Toronto, ON